OLEKSII FOKIN

DATA ANALYST

last projects: ANALYSING CONVERSION RATES

ANALYSING PRODUCT METRICS FOR SOFTWARE SERVICE COMPANY

CONTACT

- +380992918798
- ✓ oleksiifokin@gmail.com
- Vinnytsya, Ukraine



EDUCATION

1998 - 2004

IGOR SIKORSKY KYIV POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE"

Department of automation of electromechanical systems and electric drives

• Engineer electromichenic

2024

GO-IT GLOBAL

Data Analyst

HARD SKILLS

- SQL
- Python
- Processes optimisation and automation
- · Web design
- · Video editing

TOOLS

- Tableau
- Power BI
 (In the process of learning)
- Photoshop
- Illustrator

LANGUAGES

- English: Intermediate
- Ukrainian: native
- Russian: native

PROFILE SUMMARY

I have always been fascinated by the "magic" of numbers, formulas, and graphs, and in 2024, I had the opportunity to turn this passion into a profession by becoming a Data Analyst.

My experience in engineering, analysing errors in Texas Hold'em Poker (using Hold'em Manager soft), web design, video editing, as well as agriculture and optimising workflows in a military headquarters (since 24.02.2022) has taught me to work with large volumes of information, identify patterns, and make data-driven decisions.

I believe this unique skill set will help me become a productive team member and bring real value to the field of data analytics.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Private Company "GERAX"

2003 - 2008

Engineer

- Field visits to the site (reservoir park, oil pumping station).
- Preparation of technical specifications.
- Development of process automation diagrams.
- Procurement of necessary hardware according to the technical specification.
- · Creation of necessary drawings.
- Writing instructions.

Cereus Poker Network

2008-2012

Online Poker player

- Every day you learn.
- Every day after a session, you analyze your own game and the game of your opponents.
- Every day, you work on self-control.
- Analyze from 50,000 to 100,000 hands per month.
- Over 50 metrics for analysis.
- More than 50 unique opponents per month.
- Developed analytical thinking and risk management strategies by evaluating large datasets in real-time.
- Result: 5 Big Blinds per 100 hands (\$2.54/100 hands)

Military Service in the National Guard

/Military Unit A3027

2014 - 2015

Commander of the Assault Unit. Lieutenant

Military Service in the Armed Forces

27/02/24 -

now

/Military Unit A****

Company Commander. Captain

- Personnel control
- Control of military property and equipment inventory
- Maintaining the moral and psychological state of servicemen
- Ensuring timely supply of the unit
- Monitoring the technical condition of equipment and weapons
- Maintaining the combat readiness of the unit